[
    {
        "question": "And I will give you a new heart, and a new spirit I will put within you. And I will remove the heart of stone from your flesh and give you a heart of flesh. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 36:26",
        "rank": "1,146"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behold, all souls are mine; the soul of the father as well as the soul of the son is mine: the soul who sins shall die. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 18:4",
        "rank": "1,162"
    },
    {
        "question": "The hand of the LORD was upon me, and he brought me out in the Spirit of the LORD and set me down in the middle of the valley;(1) it was full of bones. Footnotes (1) 37:1 Or *plain*; also verse 2 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 37:1",
        "rank": "1,593"
    },
    {
        "question": "The soul who sins shall die. The son shall not suffer for the iniquity of the father, nor the father suffer for the iniquity of the son. The righteousness of the righteous shall be upon himself, and the wickedness of the wicked shall be upon himself. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 18:20",
        "rank": "2,015"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behold, this was the guilt of your sister Sodom: she and her daughters had pride, excess of food, and prosperous ease, but did not aid the poor and needy. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 16:49",
        "rank": "2,630"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cSon of man, raise a lamentation over the king of Tyre, and say to him, Thus says the Lord GOD: \u201cYou were the signet of perfection,(1) full of wisdom and perfect in beauty. Footnotes (1) 28:12 The meaning of the Hebrew phrase is uncertain (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 28:12",
        "rank": "2,942"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will execute great vengeance on them with wrathful rebukes. Then they will know that I am the LORD, when I lay my vengeance upon them.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 25:17",
        "rank": "2,982"
    },
    {
        "question": "Say to them, As I live, declares the Lord GOD, I have no pleasure in the death of the wicked, but that the wicked turn from his way and live; turn back, turn back from your evil ways, for why will you die, O house of Israel? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 33:11",
        "rank": "3,316"
    },
    {
        "question": "And from the midst of it came the likeness of four living creatures. And this was their appearance: they had a human likeness, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:5",
        "rank": "3,499"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cYet you say, \u2018Why should not the son suffer for the iniquity of the father?\u2019 When the son has done what is just and right, and has been careful to observe all my statutes, he shall surely live. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 18:19",
        "rank": "3,659"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under their wings on their four sides they had human hands. And the four had their faces and their wings thus: (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:8",
        "rank": "3,744"
    },
    {
        "question": "You also took your beautiful jewels of my gold and of my silver, which I had given you, and made for yourself images of men, and with them played the whore. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 16:17",
        "rank": "3,771"
    },
    {
        "question": "but each had four faces, and each of them had four wings. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:6",
        "rank": "3,840"
    },
    {
        "question": "their wings touched one another. Each one of them went straight forward, without turning as they went. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:9",
        "rank": "3,967"
    },
    {
        "question": "Their legs were straight, and the soles of their feet were like the sole of a calf\u2019s foot. And they sparkled like burnished bronze. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:7",
        "rank": "3,969"
    },
    {
        "question": "Such were their faces. And their wings were spread out above. Each creature had two wings, each of which touched the wing of another, while two covered their bodies. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:11",
        "rank": "3,991"
    },
    {
        "question": "As for the likeness of their faces, each had a human face. The four had the face of a lion on the right side, the four had the face of an ox on the left side, and the four had the face of an eagle. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:10",
        "rank": "3,993"
    },
    {
        "question": "And he said to me, \u201cSon of man, go to the house of Israel and speak with my words to them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 3:4",
        "rank": "3,999"
    },
    {
        "question": "And when the living creatures went, the wheels went beside them; and when the living creatures rose from the earth, the wheels rose. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:19",
        "rank": "4,020"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wherever the spirit wanted to go, they went, and the wheels rose along with them, for the spirit of the living creatures(1) was in the wheels. Footnotes (1) 1:20 Or *the spirit of life*; also verse 21 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:20",
        "rank": "4,096"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now as I looked at the living creatures, I saw a wheel on the earth beside the living creatures, one for each of the four of them.(1) Footnotes (1) 1:15 Hebrew *of their faces* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:15",
        "rank": "4,100"
    },
    {
        "question": "As for the likeness of the living creatures, their appearance was like burning coals of fire, like the appearance of torches moving to and fro among the living creatures. And the fire was bright, and out of the fire went forth lightning. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:13",
        "rank": "4,129"
    },
    {
        "question": "And each went straight forward. Wherever the spirit(1) would go, they went, without turning as they went. Footnotes (1) 1:12 Or *Spirit*; also twice in verse 20 and once in verse 21 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:12",
        "rank": "4,197"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the children rebelled against me. They did not walk in my statutes and were not careful to obey my rules, by which, if a person does them, he shall live; they profaned my Sabbaths. \u201cThen I said I would pour out my wrath upon them and spend my anger against them in the wilderness. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 20:21",
        "rank": "4,242"
    },
    {
        "question": "And when they went, I heard the sound of their wings like the sound of many waters, like the sound of the Almighty, a sound of tumult like the sound of an army. When they stood still, they let down their wings. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:24",
        "rank": "4,353"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the living creatures darted to and fro, like the appearance of a flash of lightning. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:14",
        "rank": "4,407"
    },
    {
        "question": "When they went, they went in any of their four directions(1) without turning as they went. Footnotes (1) 1:17 Hebrew *on their four sides* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:17",
        "rank": "4,489"
    },
    {
        "question": "When those went, these went; and when those stood, these stood; and when those rose from the earth, the wheels rose along with them, for the spirit of the living creatures was in the wheels. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:21",
        "rank": "4,510"
    },
    {
        "question": "Like the appearance of the bow that is in the cloud on the day of rain, so was the appearance of the brightness all around. Such was the appearance of the likeness of the glory of the LORD. And when I saw it, I fell on my face, and I heard the voice of one speaking. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:28",
        "rank": "4,579"
    },
    {
        "question": "For I assign to you a number of days, 390 days, equal to the number of the years of their punishment. So long shall you bear the punishment of the house of Israel. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 4:5",
        "rank": "4,628"
    },
    {
        "question": "And there came a voice from above the expanse over their heads. When they stood still, they let down their wings. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:25",
        "rank": "4,645"
    },
    {
        "question": "And their rims were tall and awesome, and the rims of all four were full of eyes all around. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:18",
        "rank": "4,704"
    },
    {
        "question": "As for the appearance of the wheels and their construction: their appearance was like the gleaming of beryl. And the four had the same likeness, their appearance and construction being as it were a wheel within a wheel. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:16",
        "rank": "4,705"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the word of the LORD came to me: (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 22:23",
        "rank": "4,732"
    },
    {
        "question": "Over the heads of the living creatures there was the likeness of an expanse, shining like awe-inspiring crystal, spread out above their heads. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:22",
        "rank": "4,798"
    },
    {
        "question": "And you took your embroidered clothes to put on them, and you offered my oil and incense before them.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 16:18",
        "rank": "4,866"
    },
    {
        "question": "He said: \"Son of man, I am sending you to the Israelites, to a rebellious nation that has rebelled against me; they and their ancestors have been in revolt against me to this very day.\"",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 2:3",
        "rank": "4,872"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"So I will not look on them with pity or spare them, but I will bring down on their own heads what they have done.\"",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 9:10",
        "rank": "4,991"
    },
    {
        "question": "And she has rebelled against my rules by doing wickedness more than the nations, and against my statutes more than the countries all around her; for they have rejected my rules and have not walked in my statutes. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 5:6",
        "rank": "4,993"
    },
    {
        "question": "And above the expanse over their heads there was the likeness of a throne, in appearance like sapphire;(1) and seated above the likeness of a throne was a likeness with a human appearance. Footnotes (1) 1:26 Or *lapis lazuli* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:26",
        "rank": "5,008"
    },
    {
        "question": "and you shall know that I am the LORD. For you have not walked in my statutes, nor obeyed my rules, but have acted according to the rules of the nations that are around you.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 11:12",
        "rank": "5,060"
    },
    {
        "question": "And under the expanse their wings were stretched out straight, one toward another. And each creature had two wings covering its body. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:23",
        "rank": "5,201"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I will break down the wall that you have smeared with whitewash, and bring it down to the ground, so that its foundation will be laid bare. When it falls, you shall perish in the midst of it, and you shall know that I am the LORD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 13:14",
        "rank": "5,222"
    },
    {
        "question": "And behold, the man clothed in linen, with the writing case at his waist, brought back word, saying, \u201cI have done as you commanded me.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 9:11",
        "rank": "5,235"
    },
    {
        "question": "And he said to me, \u201cGo in, and see the vile abominations that they are committing here.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 8:9",
        "rank": "5,251"
    },
    {
        "question": "Now I will soon pour out my wrath upon you, and spend my anger against you, and judge you according to your ways, and I will punish you for all your abominations. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 7:8",
        "rank": "5,296"
    },
    {
        "question": "He despised the oath in breaking the covenant, and behold, he gave his hand and did all these things; he shall not escape. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 17:18",
        "rank": "5,525"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cThus says the Lord GOD: This also I will let the house of Israel ask me to do for them: to increase their people like a flock. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 36:37",
        "rank": "5,567"
    },
    {
        "question": "For you are not sent to a people of foreign speech and a hard language, but to the house of Israel\u2014 (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 3:5",
        "rank": "5,632"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cIf I cause wild beasts to pass through the land, and they ravage it, and it be made desolate, so that no one may pass through because of the beasts, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 14:15",
        "rank": "5,711"
    },
    {
        "question": "But I withheld my hand and acted for the sake of my name, that it should not be profaned in the sight of the nations, in whose sight I had brought them out. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 20:22",
        "rank": "5,828"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I will spread my net over him, and he shall be taken in my snare. And I will bring him to Babylon, the land of the Chaldeans, yet he shall not see it, and he shall die there. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 12:13",
        "rank": "5,890"
    },
    {
        "question": "And upward from what had the appearance of his waist I saw as it were gleaming metal, like the appearance of fire enclosed all around. And downward from what had the appearance of his waist I saw as it were the appearance of fire, and there was brightness around him.(1) Footnotes (1) 1:27 Or *it* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 1:27",
        "rank": "5,918"
    },
    {
        "question": "So I went in and saw. And there, engraved on the wall all around, was every form of creeping things and loathsome beasts, and all the idols of the house of Israel. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 8:10",
        "rank": "6,020"
    },
    {
        "question": "Thus will I spend my wrath upon the wall and upon those who have smeared it with whitewash, and I will say to you, The wall is no more, nor those who smeared it, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 13:15",
        "rank": "6,110"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cSon of man, say to her, You are a land that is not cleansed or rained upon in the day of indignation. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 22:24",
        "rank": "6,168"
    },
    {
        "question": "When they went, they went in any of their four directions(1) without turning as they went, but in whatever direction the front wheel(2) faced, the others followed without turning as they went. Footnotes (1) 10:11 Hebrew *to their four sides* (2) 10:11 Hebrew *the head* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 10:11",
        "rank": "6,169"
    },
    {
        "question": "At the sound of the cry of your pilots the countryside shakes, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 27:28",
        "rank": "6,341"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cAs for you, son of man, surely on the day when I take from them their stronghold, their joy and glory, the delight of their eyes and their soul\u2019s desire, and also their sons and daughters, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 24:25",
        "rank": "6,386"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBut if a wicked person turns away from all his sins that he has committed and keeps all my statutes and does what is just and right, he shall surely live; he shall not die. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 18:21",
        "rank": "6,414"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore thus says the Lord GOD: Because you are more turbulent than the nations that are all around you, and have not walked in my statutes or obeyed my rules, and have not(1) even acted according to the rules of the nations that are all around you, Footnotes (1) 5:7 Some Hebrew manuscripts and Syriac lack *not* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 5:7",
        "rank": "6,459"
    },
    {
        "question": "And it came to pass, while I was prophesying, that Pelatiah the son of Benaiah died. Then I fell down on my face and cried out with a loud voice and said, \u201cAh, Lord GOD! Will you make a full end of the remnant of Israel?\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 11:13",
        "rank": "6,533"
    },
    {
        "question": "And you shall set your face toward the siege of Jerusalem, with your arm bared, and you shall prophesy against the city. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 4:7",
        "rank": "6,562"
    },
    {
        "question": "Your people will fall slain among you, and you will know that I am the LORD.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 6:7",
        "rank": "6,609"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will tie you up with ropes so that you cannot turn from one side to the other until you have finished the days of your siege.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 4:8",
        "rank": "6,687"
    },
    {
        "question": "They will come against you with weapons, chariots and wagons and with a throng of people; they will take up positions against you on every side with large and small shields and with helmets. I will turn you over to them for punishment, and they will punish you according to their standards.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 23:24",
        "rank": "6,707"
    },
    {
        "question": "The people to whom I am sending you are obstinate and stubborn. Say to them, 'This is what the Sovereign LORD says.'",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 2:4",
        "rank": "6,708"
    },
    {
        "question": "Into his right hand will come the lot for Jerusalem, where he is to set up battering rams, to give the command to slaughter, to sound the battle cry, to set battering rams against the gates, to build a ramp and to erect siege works.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 21:22",
        "rank": "6,788"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will not look on you with pity; I will not spare you. I will repay you for your conduct and for the detestable practices among you. \"Then you will know that it is I the LORD who strikes you.\"",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 7:9",
        "rank": "6,877"
    },
    {
        "question": "\"Therefore this is what the Sovereign LORD says: As surely as I live, I will bring down on his head my oath that he despised and my covenant that he broke.\"",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 17:19",
        "rank": "6,899"
    },
    {
        "question": "In front of them stood seventy elders of the house of Israel, and Jaazaniah son of Shaphan was standing among them. Each had a censer in his hand, and a fragrant cloud of incense was rising.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 8:11",
        "rank": "6,921"
    },
    {
        "question": "But the house of Israel is not willing to listen to you because they are not willing to listen to me, for the whole house of Israel is hardened and obstinate.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 3:7",
        "rank": "7,158"
    },
    {
        "question": "Not to many peoples of obscure speech and strange language, whose words you cannot understand. Surely if I had sent you to them, they would have listened to you.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 3:6",
        "rank": "7,159"
    },
    {
        "question": "And whether they listen or fail to listen \u2013 for they are a rebellious house \u2013 they will know that a prophet has been among them.",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 2:5",
        "rank": "7,354"
    },
    {
        "question": "All flesh shall see that I the LORD have kindled it; it shall not be quenched.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 20:48",
        "rank": "7,373"
    },
    {
        "question": "that you slaughtered my children and delivered them up as an offering by fire to them? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 16:21",
        "rank": "7,453"
    },
    {
        "question": "And I will scatter toward every wind all who are around him, his helpers and all his troops, and I will unsheathe the sword after them. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 12:14",
        "rank": "7,511"
    },
    {
        "question": "And the word of the LORD came to me: (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 11:14",
        "rank": "7,542"
    },
    {
        "question": "Have I any pleasure in the death of the wicked, declares the Lord GOD, and not rather that he should turn from his way and live? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 18:23",
        "rank": "7,673"
    },
    {
        "question": "the prophets of Israel who prophesied concerning Jerusalem and saw visions of peace for her, when there was no peace, declares the Lord GOD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 13:16",
        "rank": "7,674"
    },
    {
        "question": "And you, son of man, be not afraid of them, nor be afraid of their words, though briers and thorns are with you and you sit on scorpions.(1) Be not afraid of their words, nor be dismayed at their looks, for they are a rebellious house. Footnotes (1) 2:6 Or *on scorpion plants* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 2:6",
        "rank": "7,675"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cBehold, the day! Behold, it comes! Your doom has come; the rod has blossomed; pride has budded. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 7:10",
        "rank": "7,715"
    },
    {
        "question": "Therefore say, \u2018Thus says the Lord GOD: Though I removed them far off among the nations, and though I scattered them among the countries, yet I have been a sanctuary to them for a while(1) in the countries where they have gone.\u2019 Footnotes (1) 11:16 Or *in small measure* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 11:16",
        "rank": "7,833"
    },
    {
        "question": "therefore thus says the Lord GOD: Behold, I, even I, am against you. And I will execute judgments(1) in your midst in the sight of the nations. Footnotes (1) 5:8 The same Hebrew expression can mean *obey rules*, or *execute judgments*, depending on the context (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 5:8",
        "rank": "7,834"
    },
    {
        "question": "Then he brought me to the vestibule of the temple and measured the jambs of the vestibule, five cubits on either side. And the breadth of the gate was fourteen cubits, and the sidewalls of the gate(1) were three cubits on either side. Footnotes (1) 40:48 Septuagint; Hebrew lacks *was fourteen cubits, and the sidewalls of the gate* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 40:48",
        "rank": "7,903"
    },
    {
        "question": "And their whole body, their rims, and their spokes, their wings,(1) and the wheels were full of eyes all around\u2014the wheels that the four of them had. Footnotes (1) 10:12 Or *their whole body, their backs, their hands, and their wings* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 10:12",
        "rank": "7,904"
    },
    {
        "question": "even if these three men were in it, as I live, declares the Lord GOD, they would deliver neither sons nor daughters. They alone would be delivered, but the land would be desolate. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 14:16",
        "rank": "7,941"
    },
    {
        "question": "Also my bread that I gave you\u2014I fed you with fine flour and oil and honey\u2014you set before them for a pleasing aroma; and so it was, declares the Lord GOD. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 16:19",
        "rank": "8,014"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cYet I will leave some of you alive. When you have among the nations some who escape the sword, and when you are scattered through the countries, (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 6:8",
        "rank": "8,082"
    },
    {
        "question": "Behold, I have made your face as hard as their faces, and your forehead as hard as their foreheads. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 3:8",
        "rank": "8,149"
    },
    {
        "question": "on that day a fugitive will come to you to report to you the news. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 24:26",
        "rank": "8,181"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cAnd you, son of man, set your face against the daughters of your people, who prophesy out of their own hearts. Prophesy against them (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 13:17",
        "rank": "8,233"
    },
    {
        "question": "I will spread my net over him, and he shall be taken in my snare, and I will bring him to Babylon and enter into judgment with him there for the treachery he has committed against me. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 17:20",
        "rank": "8,264"
    },
    {
        "question": "As for the wheels, they were called in my hearing \u201cthe whirling wheels.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 10:13",
        "rank": "8,295"
    },
    {
        "question": "Like emery harder than flint have I made your forehead. Fear them not, nor be dismayed at their looks, for they are a rebellious house.\u201d (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 3:9",
        "rank": "8,374"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cSon of man, your brothers, even your brothers, your kinsmen,(1) the whole house of Israel, all of them, are those of whom the inhabitants of Jerusalem have said, \u2018Go far from the LORD; to us this land is given for a possession.\u2019 Footnotes (1) 11:15 Hebrew *the men of your redemption* (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 11:15",
        "rank": "8,577"
    },
    {
        "question": "None of the transgressions that he has committed shall be remembered against him; for the righteousness that he has done he shall live. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 18:22",
        "rank": "8,676"
    },
    {
        "question": "And in all your abominations and your whorings you did not remember the days of your youth, when you were naked and bare, wallowing in your blood. (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 16:22",
        "rank": "8,713"
    },
    {
        "question": "And you took your sons and your daughters, whom you had borne to me, and these you sacrificed to them to be devoured. Were your whorings so small a matter (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 16:20",
        "rank": "8,714"
    },
    {
        "question": "and say, Thus says the Lord GOD: Woe to the women who sew magic bands upon all wrists, and make veils for the heads of persons of every stature, in the hunt for souls! Will you hunt down souls belonging to my people and keep your own souls alive? (ESV)",
        "answer": "Ezekiel 13:18",
        "rank": "8,715"
    }
]